### Contact

House no sn 320-B/2 Street no 6 shamsabad Rawalpindi 03040556512 (Mobile) moeenahmed769@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/moeenahmed (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

C#

**ASP.NET MVC** 

**ASP.NET Core** 

### Certifications

Applications

React.js Essential Training
Building React and ASP.NET Core

ASP.NET Core: Middleware

Learning Entity Framework Core

### Honors-Awards

Certificate of Appreciation

# Moeen Ahmed

Consultant – Product Development at Systems Limited Pakistan

## Summary

A self-motivated and enthusiastic person, who enjoys the role of being a programmer, accepts the challenge of an ongoing work environment, and has proven ability to meet the deadline and maintain standards. Presently working as Software Engineer at Netsol Technologies. Have 2.5 years of experience in Software Development with expertise development and maintenance of desktop and web-based application using Microsoft tools and technologies.

## Experience

Systems Limited
Consultant – Product Development
December 2021 - Present (2 months)
Islāmābād, Pakistan

NETSOL Technologies Inc.
Software Engineer
December 2019 - December 2021 (2 years 1 month)

- Primary responsibilities include Development and fault fixations of WPF application
- Development of new functionality and fault fixation using front end technologies (React JS and

Angular JS)

- Worked on Model View View Model (MVVM) design pattern
- · Creation of WCF and Web API interfaces
- Extensively used Apache Subversion (SVN) version control
- Creation of re-runnable SQL scripts and optimization of existing SQL queries
- Report development using Telerik report designer.
- · Work on Microsoft workflow foundation

#### IntraSols

Associate Software Engineer - .NET Developer

January 2019 - June 2019 (6 months) Islamabad

- Development of Web applications using C#, ASP.NET MVC, Entity
   Framework
- Experience in the design and development of Restful Web API's, documentation of Web API
- Authentication of Restful API's using Identity server and JWT
- Get a hand on experience in creating Database Tables, Stored Procedures, Functions, Triggers, Cursor and Views.

## Education

University Institute of Information and Technology(UIIT-UAAR) Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2014 - 2018)